CARTER BARDELL-MUNRO

Full Stack Software Engineer

ABOUT ME

I am a full stack software engineer who has an interest in building and working on exciting software that is intuitive and provides value for consumers. I enjoy being creative and applying this to my work. After pursuing a career in marketing for five years, I felt I needed a change. Knowing the parts of marketing I enjoyed and realising I could apply them to being an engineer, I decided a career in tech was right for me. Since joining the tech industry, I have discovered I love working as part of a team, working outside my comfort zone, and pushing myself to continue learning.

So far in my career, I have enjoyed working in the frontend and I would love to continue working in this area but given my skill set, I am open to opportunities in the backend and full stack. The most important thing to me is that I continue to learn and develop my skills as a software engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Easy Crypto

01/2022 - 08/2022

Full Stack Software Engineer

Remote / New Zealand

Easy Crypto makes it easy for anyone to buy, sell, and exchange over 160+ cryptocurrencies. By focusing their efforts on a user-centred approach, they strive to simplify all aspects of the crypto experience and accelerate its adoption to facilitate financial freedom and equity to the world.

- Worked on rebuilding the existing website with a modern and easily maintained stack including React, TypeScript, and Next.js.
- · Used Chakra UI to build modular, responsive, and accessible components.
- Utilised component-driven development to build reusable components as part of a larger component library in Storybook.
- Worked on building a modern and accessible app for the existing website using React Native
- Worked within an Agile environment alongside a team of developers, designers, managers, and key stakeholders.
- Worked collaboratively alongside other junior, intermediate, and senior developers on a range of different tasks.
- Attended both sprint planning and sprint review sessions to identify what worked well and what could be worked on going forward.

PHX Consulting 10/2021 - 12/2021

Freelance Full Stack Software Engineer

Remote / New Zealand

Agile outsourced development. PHX Consulting augments a company's software delivery capabilities so that you don't have to wait to build/grow your team before you can start developing new products and platforms.

- I was tasked with rebuilding the client's frontend website with React, TypeScript, and Next.js.
- Used Chakra UI to build modular, responsive, and accessible components.
- Utilised component-driven development to build reusable components as part of a larger component library in Storybook.
- Worked within an Agile team of developers which were spread across two timezones.
- Attended sprint reviews where we showcased our work to relevant stakeholders and received feedback.

Campaign Optimisation Specialist

09/2020 - 03/2021

Hype & Dexter

Auckland

H&D future-proofs the way you find, close and service customers – With a full suite of automation solutions and digital services.

- Optimised client's HubSpot CRM portals.
- Made recommendations on how clients could improve the use of their portal.
- Created email nurture series for clients and continued to optimise based on the results.
- Wrote blog articles for both Hype & Dexter and clients on a range of different topics and industries.

SKILLS

Hard Skills

JavaScript • TypeScript • React Native •

React.js · Next.js · Redux.js · Node.js ·

Express.js · REST API's · SQLite ·

Chakra UI · HTML · CSS · Github ·

Storybook · Agile · Jira ·

Component Driven Development

Soft Skills

Strong communication • Team player •

Curious · Adaptable · Reliable · Proactive ·

Diligent • Empathetic • Attention to detail •

Flexible

FIND ME ONLINE

My Personal Website carter-dev.vercel.app

GitHub

www.github.com/carterbardellmunro

in LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/carter-bardell-munro-b20a27123/

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Music

I love discovering, sharing, and collecting music.

Spanish

After living in Argentina and travelling Latin America, I have a desire to speak this beautiful language and I continue to learn today.

Reading

I enjoy reading fantasy novels.

EXPERIENCE

Marketing Assistant

08/2018 - 12/2019

GrabOne Auckland

GrabOne offers experiences, services, products, and travel deals all over the country and beyond.

- Used the assets at NZME to promote the deals we had onsite, which included print, radio, digital, email, and social media.
- Worked closely with our Sales Team to decide what was the best possible content to promote.
- Worked closely with our Graphic Designers to make creative for our promotions and campaigns.
- Worked on major campaigns creating sales collateral, design briefs, and NZME assets to drive traffic to our website.
- Maintained company Facebook page which included daily posts, competitions, boosting targeted posts, and monitoring the inbox.

Content Deal Coordinator

04/2017 - 08/2018

GrabOne Auckland

- · Wrote creative copy and terms and conditions for onsite deals.
- Worked closely with our sales team and content team to complete and prioritise deals.
- Worked closely with clients to get their approval for deals.
- Worked in the QA team to make sure all deals onsite weren't misleading or falsely advertised.

Marketing Executive

12/2015 - 04/2017

OraHQ Auckland

- Created company blog posts and promoted them through different social channels.
- · Created targeted emails and newsletters.
- · Created and updated sales collateral.
- Managed incoming leads and provided in-person software training for our clients.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

04/2021 - 07/2021

Enspiral Dev Academy

Auckland

- The web development boot camp at EDA is an intensive, fifteen-week course designed to
 teach students industry skills while mirroring working environments. During the fifteen
 weeks, we learnt a combination of technical and human skills, providing us with a great
 understanding of how to be successful developers in the real world, both as professionals
 and empathetic humans.
- Learned skills in both the front and backend to build complete full stack applications.
- · Presented technical concepts to technical and non-technical audiences.
- Attended human skill sessions where I learnt the importance of giving and receiving feedback, attentive listening, addressing my subconscious bias, showing empathy towards others, and how to hold difficult conversations.
- In one week, built a project from scratch. My team's project was called Resonate, which
 was inspired by apps such as Tinder and Bumble. People were matched based on their
 music interests and a successful match would allow users to chat. Our final project
 allowed us to practice everything we learnt throughout the boot camp and provided us
 with a fresh set of challenges and obstacles.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.